Guide to the John Franklin Enders Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence and Topical Files, 1916-1988; Series I; 36.75' (88 boxes)
  - Journal of Clinical Investigation, 1953 (Box 38, Folder 916)
  - Journal of Experimental Medicine, 1946-1948, 1965-1969 (Box 38, Folder 917)
  - Journal of General Virology, 1966, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 918)
  - Journal of Immunology, 1929, 1946-1956 (Box 38, Folder 919-921)
  - Journal of Immunology, 1954-1960, undated (Box 39, Folder 922)
  - Journal of Infectious Diseases, 1967-1976 undated (Box 39, Folder 923-931)
  - Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 932)
  - Journal of Pediatrics, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 933)
  - Journal of the National Cancer Institute, 1960-1966, 1969, undated (Box 39, Folder 934)
  - Journal of Virology, 1966-1970 (Box 39, Folder 935)
  - Joy, Arthur F., 1955 (Box 39, Folder 936)
  - Kahn, Reuben L., 1947 (Box 39, Folder 937)
  - Kalckar, Hermann, 1962-1965, undated (Box 39, Folder 938, Box 38)
  - Kalter, Seymour S., 1949, 1954 (Box 39, Folder 939)
  - Kanazawa, K., 1955, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 940)
    See also: box 45, folder 1120
  - Kane, Lewis W., 1943-1946 (Box 40, Folder 941)
  - Kane, Robert, 1943 (Box 40, Folder 942)
  - Kanellakis, Athanasios P., 1950, 1963-1964 (Box 40, Folder 943)
  - Karel, Leonard, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 944)
  - Karelitz, Samuel, 1962-1963 (Box 40, Folder 945)
  - Karpas, Abraham, 1964-1978, undated (Box 40, Folder 946)
  - Karzon, David T., 1960, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 947)
  - Kass, Edward, 1968-1969 (Box 40, Folder 948)
  - Katz, Samuel L., 1960-1963 (Box 40, Folder 949)
    See also: box 50, folders 1214-1217
  - Katz, Samuel L., 1964-1971, 1976, undated (Box 40, Folder 950-951)
  - Kauffmann, Fritz, 1944 (Box 40, Folder 952)
  - Kaufman, Herbert E., 1959, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 953)
  - Kawarabayashi, Tadao, 1958-1959 (Box 40, Folder 954)
  - Keefer, Chester S., 1936, 1959, 1962-1964 (Box 40, Folder 955)
  - Kempe, C. Henry, 1947, 1951, 1954, 1958-1960, 1968, 1972, undated (Box 40, Folder 956)
    See also: box 50, folders 1218-1220
  - Kenny, Elizabeth, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 957)
  - Kenworthy, Rosalind, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 958)
  - Keogh, Esmond V., 1945, 1955, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 959)
  - Khoury, George, 1968-1970, 1974-1977, undated (Box 40, Folder 960)
  - Kibrick, Sidney, 1949-1950, 1954-1959 (Box 40, Folder 961-962)
  - Kibrick, Sidney, 1960-1963, 1968, undated (Box 41, Folder 963)
  - Kidd, John G., 1952 (Box 41, Folder 964)
  - Kilbourne, Edwin D., 1955 (Box 41, Folder 965)
  - Kilham, Lawrence, 1946-1956, 1960-1965, 1968, undated (Box 41, Folder 966)
  - King, Martin Luther, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 967)
  - Kingsley Trust Association, 1956-1959 (Box 41, Folder 968)
  - Kinsey, V. E., 1943 (Box 41, Folder 969)
  - Kirsh, David, 1945 (Box 41, Folder 970)
  - Kit, Saul, 1974, undated (Box 41, Folder 971)
  - Kitaoka, Masami, 1957, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 972)
  - Kiyasu, William, 1964 (Box 41, Folder 973)
  - Klenk, Hans-Dieter, 1972, undated (Box 41, Folder 974)
  - Kligerman, S., 1943 (Box 41, Folder 975)
  - Klimazewski, Wanda, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 976)
  - Klúver, Heinrich, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 977)
  - Kohn, Alexander, 1966-1967, undated (Box 41, Folder 978)
  - Kohn, Henry I., 1967, 1971-1972 (Box 41, Folder 979)
  - Koprowski, Hilary, 1946, 1952-1957, 1966-1967, undated (Box 41, Folder 980)
  - Kovacs, Ernest, 1954-1956 (Box 41, Folder 981)
  - Kramer, S. D., undated (Box 41, Folder 982)
  - Krause, A. K., 1935 (Box 41, Folder 983)
  - Krayer, Otto, 1942, 1948, 1952 (Box 41, Folder 984)
  - Krech, Ulrich H., 1952 (Box 41, Folder 985)
  - Krugman, Saul, 1959, 1965-1971 (Box 41, Folder 986)
    See also: box 50, folder 1221
  - Krugman, Saul, 1972-1973, 1976, undated (Box 41, Folder 987)
  - Kumm, Henry W., 1951, 1957-1963, undated (Box 41, Folder 988)
  - Kunz, Lawrence J., 1949-1954, 1957, 1975-1976, undated (Box 41, Folder 989)
  - Kurotchkin, Timothy, 1940-1945 (Box 41, Folder 990)
  - Laboratory Resources Program, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 991)
  - La Busquiere, R., 1966-1967 (Box 41, Folder 992)
  - Lal, S., 1940, 1943, undated (Box 41, Folder 993)
  - Landauer, Kenneth S., 1952-1954 (Box 41, Folder 994)
  - Landis, Eugene M., 1944-1948, 1967 (Box 41, Folder 995)
  - Landsteiner, Karl, 1936, 1941 (Box 41, Folder 996)
  - Lang, David J., 1962-1966, 1969-1971, 1974-1975, undated (Box 41, Folder 997-998)
  - Langmuir, Alexander D., 1955, 1962-1963 (Box 42, Folder 999)
  - Larimer, Robert C., 1947-1950 (Box 42, Folder 1000)
  - Larin, Nicholas M., 1962-1963 (Box 42, Folder 1001)
  - Larkin, Edward P., 1959-1960 (Box 42, Folder 1002)
  - Lasker Award, 1954-1956, 1960-1964 (Box 42, Folder 1003)
  - Lassa virus materials, 1970-1976 (Box 42, Folder 1004)
  - Lattimer, John K., 1970 (Box 42, Folder 1005)
  - Lauffer, Max A., 1955, 1958-1959 (Box 42, Folder 1006)
  - Lawrence, John S., 1939 (Box 42, Folder 1007)
  - Lawson, G. M., 1940 (Box 42, Folder 1008)
  - Leas, Martha, 1959-1962, 1966, 1970-1971, undated (Box 42, Folder 1009)
  - Le Bouvier, George, 1951-1955, 1969-1971 (Box 42, Folder 1010)
  - Lederle Laboratories, Inc., 1939-1945 (Box 42, Folder 1011)
  - Lederle Laboratories, Inc., 1947, 1951-1963, undated (Box 42, Folder 1012)
  - Lederman, Morton, 1956-1958 (Box 42, Folder 1013)
  - Lee, Henry F., 1963 (Box 42, Folder 1014)
  - Lee, Roger I., 1943 (Box 42, Folder 1015)
  - Legislation: Massachusetts and U. S., 1956, 1965-1967 (Box 42, Folder 1016)
  - Lehigh University. Department of Bacteriology, 1951 (Box 42, Folder 1017)
  - Lehnherr, Earl R., 1942 (Box 42, Folder 1018)
  - Leibovitz, Albert, 1957 (Box 42, Folder 1019)
  - Lejins, Janis, 1957, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 1020)
  - Lejins, Lolita, undated (Box 42, Folder 1021)
  - Lennette, Edwin H., 1947, 1951-1952, 1957-1958, 1967-1968, 1972-1973 (Box 42, Folder 1022)
  - Leonard, John C., 1953-1954 (Box 42, Folder 1023)
  - Lépine, Pierre, 1952-1955, 1962, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 1024)
  - Lerner, A. Martin, 1962, 1966, 1970 (Box 42, Folder 1025)
  - Leuchtenberger, Cecilie, 1960-1970, 1973, undated (Box 42, Folder 1026)
  - Levens, Ernest and Jeannette, 1945-1947, 1950, 1960-1962 (Box 42, Folder 1027)
  - Levin, Myron, 1969-1970 (Box 42, Folder 1028)
  - Levin, Myron, 1971-1973, undated (Box 43, Folder 1029)
  - Levine, Maurice, 1957 (Box 43, Folder 1030)
  - Levinthal, Jeana D., 1962-1967 (Box 43, Folder 1031)
  - Lewis, James, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 1032)
  - Ley, Herbert L., 1948-1950, 1957 (Box 43, Folder 1033)
  - Lherisson, Camille, 1940 (Box 43, Folder 1034)
  - Li, C. P., 1940, 1951-1954, 1958 (Box 43, Folder 1035)
  - Library of Congress, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 1036)
  - Liebhaber, Harvey, 1968-1971, undated (Box 43, Folder 1037)
  - Life, 1954-1956 (Box 43, Folder 1038)
  - Lilly Award, 1950, 1955, 1962-1963, undated (Box 43, Folder 1039)
  - Lilly Research Laboratories, 1952, 1955-1956, 1965, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 1040)
  - Linz, R., 1940 (Box 43, Folder 1041)
  - Lippard, Vernon W., 1959 (Box 43, Folder 1042)
  - Lipson, Martha J., 1957-1958 (Box 43, Folder 1043)
  - Lisco, Hermann, 1961, 1971-1973, undated (Box 43, Folder 1044)
  - Little, Brown and Co., 1940, 1960, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 1045)
  - Little, Robert, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 1046)
  - Liu, Chien, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 1047)
  - Liv, P. Y., 1942-1943 (Box 43, Folder 1048)
  - Locke, Edwin A., 1937 (Box 43, Folder 1049)
  - Logan, J., 1953 (Box 43, Folder 1050)
  - London, Howard J., 1959 (Box 43, Folder 1051)
  - Longcope, Warfield, 1942, 1945 (Box 43, Folder 1052)
  - Loosli, Clayton G., 1953, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 1053)
  - Lowe, Yolanda, 1967, 1970, undated (Box 43, Folder 1054)
  - Loyola University Medical School, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 1055)
  - Lucas, Alfred M., 1941 (Box 43, Folder 1056)
  - Lundbeck, Holger, 1962, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 1057)
  - Luria, S. E., 1960, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 1058)
  - Lurie, Max B., 1939-1941 (Box 43, Folder 1059)
  - Lwoff, André, 1953-1954, 1959-1960, 1963-1969, undated (Box 43, Folder 1060)
  - Lynch, John, 1947 (Box 43, Folder 1061)
  - Lyons, Champ, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 1062)
  - McAllister, Robert M., 1951-1952, 1965-1966 (Box 43, Folder 1063)
  - McBean, A. Marshall, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 1064)
  - McBride, John Hammond, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 1065)
  - MacCallum, F. O., 1950-1951, 1956-1958, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 1066)
  - McCarthy, Clarke G., 1954 (Box 43, Folder 1067)
  - McCarthy, Eugene, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 1068)
  - McCarthy, Kevin, 1953-1967 (Box 43, Folder 1069-1070)
  - McCarthy, Robert E., 1968-1970 (Box 43, Folder 1071)
  - Macchiavello, Attilio, 1939 (Box 43, Folder 1072)
  - MacCleod, E., 1967 (Box 43, Folder 1073)
  - McClung, L. S., 1941, 1947, 1964, 1970, undated (Box 43, Folder 1074)
  - McCollum, Robert W., 1964-1965, 1971, 1975-1976 (Box 44, Folder 1075)
  - McComb, James A., 1956-1959, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 1076)
  - McCrie, Jan G., 1962 (Box 44, Folder 1077)
  - McGee, Andrew R., 1967-1968, undated (Box 44, Folder 1078)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1943, 1958, 1965, undated (Box 44, Folder 1079)
  - Mack, W. N., 1952, 1958 (Box 44, Folder 1080)
    See also: box 45, folder 1137 See also: box 46, folder 1138
  - McKhann, Charles F., 1936, 1944 (Box 44, Folder 1081)
  - McLean, C. C., 1968 (Box 44, Folder 1082)
  - McLean, Donald M., 1954, 1957 (Box 44, Folder 1083)
  - McLimans, William F., 1958-1959, 1968, undated (Box 44, Folder 1084)
    See also: box 45, folder 1122
  - MacMillan Company, 1946-1951, 1959 (Box 44, Folder 1085)
  - Magasanik, Boris, 1970-1971 (Box 44, Folder 1086)
  - Magill, T. P., 1950-1951 (Box 44, Folder 1087)
  - Maisel, John
    See: box 47, folder 1175
  - Maitland, H. B., 1946, 1952 (Box 44, Folder 1088)
  - Makino, Satoshi, 1972-1974, undated (Box 44, Folder 1089)
  - Malherbe, Hubert, 1952-1960, 1967-1970, 1974, 1977, undated (Box 44, Folder 1090)
  - Mallory, Tracy B., 1949-1950 (Box 44, Folder 1091)
  - Manual of Drugs and Diseases, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 1092)
  - Marchessault, Victor, 1960, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 1093)
  - Marcus, Philip I., 1971 (Box 44, Folder 1094)
  - Margolis, George, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 1095)
  - Markham, Floyd S., 1960, undated (Box 44, Folder 1096)
  - Marlow, F. William, 1941 (Box 44, Folder 1097)
  - Marmion, B. P., 1951, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 1098)
  - Marquis-Who's Who Inc., 1964-1965 (Box 44, Folder 1099)
  - Mary Leo Rita, Sister, S. S. M., 1958 (Box 44, Folder 1100)
  - Mason, Hermann C., 1954 (Box 44, Folder 1101)
  - Massachusetts Biologic Laboratories, 1970-1972 (Box 44, Folder 1102)
  - Massachusetts Civil Defense Agency. Communicable Disease Section, 1951, undated (Box 44, Folder 1103)
  - Massachusetts Department of Public Health
    See also: box 75, folders 1659-1662
  - Massachusetts Eye and Ear Infirmary (Box 44, Folder 1107)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, 1956, 1960-1961, 1965, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 1108)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology
    - Biology Department, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 1109)
    - Program in Health Sciences, 1971, undated (Box 44, Folder 1110)
  - Massachusetts Medical Society
    - General, 1942, 1947, 1952, 1955 (Box 44, Folder 1111)
    - Lincoln Commission, 1950-1951 (Box 44, Folder 1112)
    - Lincoln Commission, 1952-1953, undated (Box 45, Folder 1113)
  - Masse, Nathalie, 1971-1972 (Box 45, Folder 1114)
  - Mata, Leonardo, 1962-1964, undated (Box 45, Folder 1115)
  - Materials received for testing, 1945-1949 (Box 45, Folder 1116)
  - Materials received for testing, 1952-1965 (Box 45, Folder 1117-1130)
  - Materials received with case histories, 1943, 1948-1950 (Box 45, Folder 1131)
  - Materials sent out, 1936, 1943-1958 June (Box 45, Folder 1132-1137)
  - Materials sent out, 1958 July-1966, 1967, n.d (Box 46, Folder 1138-1146)
  - Materials sent out, 1968-1971 (Box 46, Folder 1147)
  - Materials sent out: Katz, Samuel L., 1960-1963 (Box 46, Folder 1148)
  - Materials sent out: Katz, Samuel L., 1964-1965 (Box 46, Folder 1149)
  - Materials sent out: lists, 1946-1962, 1961-1976 (Box 46, Folder 1150)
  - Matson, Donald, 1968-1969 (Box 46, Folder 1151)
  - Maxcy, Ellis C., 1967 (Box 46, Folder 1152)
  - Maxcy, Kenneth, 1950-1951 (Box 46, Folder 1153)
  - May, Charles D., 1955 (Box 46, Folder 1154)
  - Mayer, Edward, 1942 (Box 46, Folder 1155)
  - Mead, Johnson and Company, 1956 (Box 47, Folder 1156)
  - Meadow, Henry, 1957 (Box 47, Folder 1157)
  - Meakins, J. F., 1940, 1960-1961 (Box 47, Folder 1158)
  - Means, J. H., 1943-1945, 1955, 1960 (Box 47, Folder 1159)
  - Measles
    - Adams, John M., 1956, 1960, 1962 (Box 47, Folder 1160)
    - Bibliographies, 1959, undated (Box 47, Folder 1161)
    - Black, Francis R., 1958-1964, 1967 (Box 47, Folder 1162)
    - Communicable Disease Center, 1961-1963 (Box 47, Folder 1163)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1954-1966 (Box 47, Folder 1164)
      See also: box 40, folder 956 See also: box 76, folder 1681 See also: box 87, folder 2044
    - Encephalitis, 1959-1961 (Box 47, Folder 1165)
    - Exhibit, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 1166)
    - Film for the Armed Forces Epidemiological Board, 1971 (Box 47, Folder 1167)
    - Gajdusek, D. Carleton, 1961-1962 (Box 47, Folder 1168)
    - Giant cell pneumonia, 1961 (Box 47, Folder 1169)
    - Gibbs, Erna and Frederic, 1958-1961, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 1170)
    - Hilleman, Maurice R., 1955-1968 (Box 47, Folder 1171-1173)
    - International Children's Center: seminar on the epidemiology and prevention of measles and rubella, 1963-1964 (Box 47, Folder 1174)
    - Maisel, John, 1963 (Box 47, Folder 1175)
    - Measles virus vs. distemper sera, undated (Box 47, Folder 1176)
    - Memorabilia, 1957 (Box 47, Folder 1177)
    - Meyer, Harry M., 1960-1968 (Box 47, Folder 1178)
    - National Institutes of Health
      - Conference on measles, 1959 (Box 47, Folder 1179)
      - Division of Biologics Standards
        - Meeting: 1958 Apr (Box 47, Folder 1180)
        - Meeting: 1960 Nov, 1958-1961 (Box 48, Folder 1181)
        - Meeting: 1962 Nov, 1962, undated (Box 48, Folder 1182)
      - International Conference on Measles Immunization, 1961-1962 (Box 48, Folder 1183)
      - Meeting, 1958 Jun, 1958, 1962 (Box 48, Folder 1184)
    - Paul, David, 1962 (Box 48, Folder 1185)
    - Plum Island animal disease laboratory, 1956-1964, undated (Box 48, Folder 1186-1188)
    - Program for Harvard Medicine: President's meeting, 1961 Mar 17 (Box 48, Folder 1189)
    - Rubella correspondence, 1958-1969, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 1190)
    - Siber, George, 1969, 1973, 1978, 1982-1985 (Box 48, Folder 1191)
    - Sisson, Warren R., 1964 (Box 48, Folder 1192)
    - Stokes, Joseph, 1947-1952, 1957, 1960-1962 (Box 48, Folder 1193)
    - Study: correspondence, 1949, 1953-1958, undated (Box 48, Folder 1194)
    - Surgeon General Ad Hoc Advisory Committee on Measles Control, 1963 January-Jul, undated (Box 49, Folder 1195-1196)
    - Television broadcast, 1963 (Box 49, Folder 1197)
      See also: box 72, folder 1607
    - United Nations Science Conference, 1962-1963 (Box 49, Folder 1198)
    - Warren, Joel, 1958-1963 (Box 49, Folder 1199)
    - Wedgewood, Ralph, 1960 (Box 49, Folder 1200)
    - World Health Organization: meeting, 1961 Nov 10 (Box 49, Folder 1201)
  - Measles vaccine
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1959-1967, 1971 (Box 49, Folder 1202-1203)
    - Economic research, 1965-1966 (Box 49, Folder 1204)
    - Massachusetts Public Health Service: Measles Vaccine Program, 1966 (Box 49, Folder 1205)
    - Monkey experiment
      - Katz's data, 1957-1959 (Box 49, Folder 1206)
      - Summary, undated (Box 49, Folder 1207)
    - Publicity, 1961 (Box 49, Folder 1208)
    - "Recommendations Relating to the Manufacture of Measles Vaccine, Inactivated and Attenuated", 1961-1963 (Box 49, Folder 1209)
    - Studies and trials
      - Ashley study on Monhegan Island, Maine, 1962 (Box 50, Folder 1210)
      - Brookline, Massachusetts: field testing, 1961-1962 (Box 50, Folder 1211)
      - Curnen trial at Oxford, North Carolina, 1959-1960 (Box 50, Folder 1212)
      - Haggerty study at Children's Hospital Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts, 1959-1960, undated (Box 50, Folder 1213)
      - Katz field trial in Nigeria, 1959-1963, 1969, undated (Box 50, Folder 1214-1216)
      - Katz trial at Fernald State School, Waverly, Massachusetts, 1958-1960, undated (Box 50, Folder 1217)
      - Kempe trials in Denver, Colorado, 1958-1962, undated (Box 50, Folder 1218-1220)
      - Krugman trials at Willowbrook State School, Staten Island, New York, 1959-1963, undated (Box 50, Folder 1221)
      - Lepow, Gray, and Robbins study at Parmadale Orphanage, Cleveland, Ohio, 1959-1960, undated (Box 50, Folder 1222)
      - McCrumb and Woodward trial in St. Joseph, Missouri, 1958-1960 (Box 50, Folder 1223)
      - Paul et al. trial in New Haven, Connecticut, 1958-1959, 1963, undated (Box 51, Folder 1224)
      - Schwachman study at Maine Medical Center, 1960-1962, undated (Box 51, Folder 1225)
      - Schwartz trials at Pitman-Moore Company, 1952, 1955-1956, 1965 (Box 51, Folder 1226)
      - Sherry trials at Metropolitan State School, Waltham, Massachusetts, 1961 (Box 51, Folder 1227)
  - Medearis, Donald N., 1955-1961, 1964-1965, 1968-1969, 1972-1973, 1981, undated (Box 51, Folder 1228-1231)
  - Medical College of Virginia, 1950 (Box 51, Folder 1232)
  - Medical Exchange Club, 1946, 1949-1973, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 1233-1235)
  - Medical Foundation, 1970, 1973-1974 (Box 51, Folder 1236)
  - Medical Letter, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 1237)
  - Medical News, 1956, 1960-1961 (Box 51, Folder 1238)
  - Medical Tribune, 1966-1967 (Box 51, Folder 1239)
  - Medical World News, 1963-1967 (Box 51, Folder 1240)
  - Medinger, Ann, 1969, undated (Box 51, Folder 1241)
  - Meenan, Patrick, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 1242)
  - Melendez, Luis, 1954-1962, 1966, 1969 (Box 51, Folder 1243)
  - Melendez, Luis, 1971-1976, undated (Box 51, Folder 1244)
    See also: box 31, folders 739-740
  - Melnick, Joseph D., 1943, 1948-1957 (Box 52, Folder 1245)
    See also: box 32, folder 769
  - Melnick, Joseph D., 1961-1968, 1971-1973, undated (Box 52, Folder 1246)
  - Melnick, Sarah, 1957, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 1247)
  - Menkin, Valy, 1943-1945, 1953-1960, undated (Box 52, Folder 1248-1249)
  - Merck, Sharp and Dohne, 1957, 1965, 1971, 1978 (Box 52, Folder 1250)
  - Mérieux, Charles, 1958, 1961-1964 (Box 52, Folder 1251)
  - Merigan, Thomas, 1968-1969 (Box 52, Folder 1252)
  - Methods and techniques, early, 1934-1942, 1948, undated (Box 52, Folder 1253-1254)
  - Metz, David H., 1972-1976, undated (Box 52, Folder 1255)
  - Meyer, Harry M., 1960, 1964-1966, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 1256)
    See also: box 47, folder 1178
  - Meyer, Karl F., 1941-1951, 1954, 1964-1965 (Box 52, Folder 1257)
  - Michigan Department of Health, 1948 (Box 52, Folder 1258)
  - Microbiological Associates
    - General, 1948-1966 (Box 52, Folder 1259)
    - Monkey kidney, 1959-1963 (Box 53, Folder 1260)
  - Middlebrook, Gardner, 1944 (Box 53, Folder 1261)
  - Military Medico-Dental Symposium, 1956-1957 (Box 53, Folder 1262)
  - Miller, George, 1961-1979, 1984, undated (Box 53, Folder 1263-1271)
  - Miller, Mary, 1973-1974 (Box 54, Folder 1272)
  - Mills, John, 1965-1966 (Box 54, Folder 1273)
  - Mills, Libby, 1945, undated (Box 54, Folder 1274)
  - Milovanovic, Milan V., 1954-1977, undated (Box 54, Folder 1275-1276)
  - Milzer, Albert, 1944, 1952-1957, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 1277)
  - Mims, Cedric A., 1962-1964, undated (Box 54, Folder 1278)
  - Miner, Leroy, 1943 (Box 54, Folder 1279)
  - Minot, George, 1945-1948 (Box 54, Folder 1280)
  - Minsky, Marvin, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 1281)
  - Mitus, Anna, 1955-1964, 1968, 1973, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 1282)
  - Modern Medicine award, 1955-1956, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 1283)
  - Monaci, Vittorio, 1955-1956, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 1284)
  - Monkeys: certificate of need, etc., 1942, 1945, 1949, 1955-1960, 1963, 1969, undated (Box 54, Folder 1285)
  - Monroe, Robert T., 1941, undated (Box 54, Folder 1286)
  - Moolten, Sylvan, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 1287)
  - Moore, Francis, 1964-1966, 1973 (Box 54, Folder 1288)
  - Morgan, Councilman, 1954 (Box 54, Folder 1289)
  - Morgan, Herbert R., 1942-1961, 1965-1966, 1970, undated (Box 54, Folder 1290-1291)
  - Morgante, Odosca, 1955, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 1292)
  - Morison, Samuel E., 1945 (Box 54, Folder 1293)
  - Morrice, George, 1945 (Box 54, Folder 1294)
  - Morse, Fred W., 1943 (Box 54, Folder 1295)
  - Mortada, Soad M., 1956-1957 (Box 54, Folder 1296)
  - Mosley, James W., 1957-1961, undated (Box 54, Folder 1297-1298)
  - Mountain, Isabel M., 1948, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 1299)
  - Muckenfuss, Ralph S., 1936 (Box 54, Folder 1300)
  - Mudd, Stuart, 1964-1967 (Box 54, Folder 1301)
  - Mueller, J. Howard
    - General, 1940-1941, 1944-1953, undated (Box 55, Folder 1302-1303)
    - Memorial material, 1954-1961, 1965, 1971-1972, 1975, undated (Box 55, Folder 1304-1305)
  - Mumps
    - Chapter in "Diagnostic, Procedures", 1953-1954, 1957, 1965 (Box 55, Folder 1306)
    - Children's Hospital of Philadelphia: staff, 1943-1945, undated (Box 55, Folder 1307)
    - Commission on Measles and Mumps. Board for the Investigation of Influenza and Other Epidemic Diseases, Preventive Medicine Service Office of Surgeon General, U. S. Army, 1941-1943 March (Box 55, Folder 1308)
    - Commission on Measles and Mumps, etc., 1943 April-1945 Nov, 1946-1947, undated (Box 55, Folder 1309-1315)
    - Complement fixations: blood sera sent for diagnosis, 1946-1947 (Box 55, Folder 1316)
    - Correspondence, general, 1942-1951 (Box 56, Folder 1317-1318)
    - Correspondence, general, 1953-1961, 1965-1968, undated (Box 56, Folder 1319)
    - Data
      - Encephalitis cases, 1942-1946, undated (Box 56, Folder 1320-1324)
      - Miscellaneous, 1943-1946, undated (Box 56, Folder 1325)
      - Monkey, 1942 (Box 56, Folder 1326)
    - Hilleman, Maurice, 1968-1969, undated (Box 56, Folder 1327)
    - References, undated (Box 56, Folder 1328)
    - Skin test reports, 1948 (Box 56, Folder 1329)
    - Specimens, 1945-1952 (Box 56, Folder 1330)
    - Studies
      - Army Medical School, 1943-1945, undated (Box 56, Folder 1331)
      - Atlanta Dental College, 1944 (Box 56, Folder 1332)
      - Camp McCoy, Wisconsin, 1943 (Box 56, Folder 1333)
      - Camp Pickett, Virginia, 1943 (Box 56, Folder 1334)
      - Children's Hospital (Boston), 1943-1946 (Box 57, Folder 1335)
      - George School, undated (Box 57, Folder 1336)
      - Harvard Medical School Students, 1942-1945, undated (Box 57, Folder 1337)
      - Haynes Memorial Hospital (Allston, Massachusetts), 1943-1945 (Box 57, Folder 1338)
      - New England Home for Little Wanderers, 1945 (Box 57, Folder 1339)
      - New Lisbon, New Jersey, 1943 (Box 57, Folder 1340)
      - Peabody Home, 1942, 1945, undated (Box 57, Folder 1341)
      - Pennhurst School (Pennsylvania), 1944-1945 (Box 57, Folder 1342-1344)
      - Private case groups in Boston and Philadelphia, 1943-1945 (Box 57, Folder 1345)
      - St. Paul's School (Concord, New Hampshire), 1944 (Box 57, Folder 1346)
      - Skillman, New Jersey, 1943-1946 (Box 57, Folder 1347)
      - Tufts Medical School (Boston), 1945-1946 (Box 57, Folder 1348)
    - Vaccine, 1968 (Box 57, Folder 1349)
  - Murray, E. G. D., 1948-1950 (Box 57, Folder 1350)
  - Murray, Edward, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 1351)
  - Murray, Joseph E., 1964-1965, 1968-1969 (Box 57, Folder 1352)
  - Murray, Margaret R., 1953, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 1353)
  - Murray, Roderick, 1960-1961, 1964-1970, undated (Box 57, Folder 1354)
  - Musser, Samuel J., 1958, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 1355)
  - Nadel, Marvin K., 1955, 1958, undated (Box 58, Folder 1356)
  - Naficy, Kiarash, 1960-1962 (Box 58, Folder 1357)
  - Naficy, Kiarash, 1963-1968 (Box 58, Folder 1358-1360)
  - Naficy, Kiarash, 1972-1973, undated (Box 58, Folder 1361)
  - Nagata, Ikuya, 1959-1977 (Box 58, Folder 1362-1363)
  - Nahmias, André J., 1968 (Box 58, Folder 1364)